Kartik Anand

Collaborative professional with 4 years of experience in the financial services industry. Excellent problem-solving skills that help drive results in an extremely fast-paced environment. Background in data science, data engineering and analytics. Strategic and decisive thinker with strong communication skills and interpersonal abilities.





anandkartik97@gmail.com



+65-97850414



anandkartik97.streamlit.app/



in linkedin.com/in/kartikanand97

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Developer - Data **Olam Financial Services**

Singapore

- Developed green field Data Ecosystem for commodity futures and equities asset classes. Implemented relational database structures and managed data workflows using Apache Airflow
- Built real-time data validation pipeline for Equities Trading Desk. Defined and tested data expectations, validated data integrity and monitored data quality to improve accuracy and reduce errors
- Designed MIS application to monitor Quant fund portfolio performance metrics enabling centralized reporting and data-driven strategies
- Performed market data streaming analytics using real-time tick by tick data connectors

Data Analytics Associate NatWest Group

11/2021 - 10/2022

- Text analytics on historic audit reports for readability, sentiment & wordcloud analysis aiding audit team validate the adherence of audit report ratings
- Lead design and execution of data intensive tests for Risk and Finance
- Developed spreadsheet analyzer tool that retrieves cellular information from EUDAs and uses visualizations to highlight the areas subject to higher risks
- Extensively managed and developed various self-service tools and dashboards for Global Data Analytics Team

Technology Analyst

Citicorp Services India Pvt. Ltd.

08/2019 - 11/2021

- Developed microservices using Java for OneConnect a low latency global order routing platform
- Automated the outbound flow for SFTR Regulatory Reporting by using Apache Camel routing framework to generate and transfer the outbound files

Data Science and Analytics Intern

Royal Bank of Scotland

05/2018 - 07/2018

Gurugram, India

 Conceptualized and delivered 2 self-service automated tools written in Python reducing the data validation TAT by 80%

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology (Software Engineering)

Delhi Technological University

2015 - 2019

8.71 CGPA (First Division)

Class XII

Salwan Public School, New Delhi

2014 - 2015

96.6% (School Topper)

10 CGPA (School Topper)

Class X

2012 - 2013

Salwan Public School, New Delhi

SKILLS



ACHIEVEMENTS AND AWARDS

Citi Gratitude Platinum Award ; Citi Gratitude Gold Award ; Citi Gratitude Copper Award

Recognized with exemplary performance awards for reaching the extra mile to deliver in all endeavors by Senior Management

HackBangalore'18

Awarded for the best pitch and idea by Mercedes Benz R&D Germany

School Topper Award

Award for Academic Excellence (School Topper) in 2015

CBSE Certificate of Merit

Awarded for being in top 0.1% of successful candidates in Physics

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Fraud Analytics

- Compared various Supervised Machine Learning techniques like Logistic Regression, Decision Trees, Naive Bayes, Support Vector Machine to detect fraud in publicly available credit card data set
- Published research paper in <u>Springer Nature Singapore</u>

Real Time Face Recognition

Generated training data set of images to build a classifier to Extracted faces from live recognize faces. Extracted faces from live video using HaarCascades Classifier, followed by face recognition using KNN

CERTIFICATIONS

Alteryx Designer Core Certification

Alteryx.com

The Complete Introduction to Data Analytics with Tableau

Udemy

POSITIONS OF RESPONSIBILITY

CSR - Social Contributor

Successfully led a team of 20+ volunteers to organise Sport Day event for 150+ primary school students in association with New Vision NGO

Tech Head - Annual Literary Fest, DTU

Successfully led a team of 20+ people and created a visually appealing web portal responsible for registration of 1200+ participants